Guide to the Reynolds Price Papers, 1880-2014 RL.01050
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Duke University, 1960-2010, undated
  - Recordings of Price at Duke, 1973-2006, undated
    - Waiting at Dachau and Gender in Fiction, 1974 Jan 3, 1975 Jan 15 (Box 299, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0090)
    - Reading Milton, 1975 May 18-June (Box 299, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0088)
    - Milton class lectures, 1976 Jan-Apr; 26 items (Box 299, Audio-cassette RL01050-CS-0062 - RL01050-CS-0087)
      Audio recordings of Price's lectures on John Milton, including titles Psalm 114; Fair Infant; Nativity Ode; Allez and Pens; Comms; Lycidas; Damon; Of Education; Sonnets; and, Samson Agonistes.
    - A Weekend with Reynolds Price - Master Class w/ Doris Betts, 2001 Nov 3 (Box 298, Video-disc RL01050-DVCAM-0001)
    - Milton lectures and classes, 2006 Jan-Apr, undated; 22 items (Box 348, Audio-disc RL01050-MD-0001 - RL01050-MD-0022)
- Writings by others, 1935-2009, undated
  Manuscripts (some of them photocopies) sent to Price by fellow authors and by students make up the (6) Writings by Others Series. A few of these include commentary by Price. Both published and unpublished works of poetry and prose are included. A few bibliographies of Price's work are arranged at the end of this series.
  - Adcock, Betty, 2000 (Box 208)
    Intervale: New and Selected Poems
  - Alexander, Corabel, 1995 (Box 208)
    All Talk; Crab Bait; It's Probably Nothing; A Far Cry; Homesick; Traps
  - Allen, Dorothy, 2005 Mar 6 (Box 208)
    Collection of poems
  - Anderson, Jeffrey, 1980-1981 (Box 208)
    Journal of Trip to Israel, December 1980 - January 1981
  - Applewhite, James, 1970, 1997 (Box 208)
    City of Infamy; Daytime and Starlight
  - Auden, W. H., 1956 (Box 208)
    Oratio Creweiana MCMLVIII
  - Barker, Franklin, 1971 (Box 208)
    Hometown Girls
  - Beebe, Chris, 1975; 2 folders (Box 208)
    An Optimist's Journal
  - Bell, Madison Smartt, 2000 (Box 208)
    Teaching Notes on Price for the Goucher College Fiction Workshop
  - Benay Brothers, The, undated (Box 208)
    Samurai
  - Bhatia, Lakshmi, undated (Box 208)
    Precious Pearls
  - Bhubaneswar, Chaya G., undated; 3 folders (Box 208)
    The Last Day
  - Blackburn, Alexander, 1994 (Box 208)
    The Long Habit of Living, Essay on William Maxwell Blackburn
  - Bly, Robert, 2004, undated; 2 folders (Box 209)
    The Lightning Should Have Fallen on Ghalib; The Insanity of Empire: A Book of Poems Against the Iraq War
  - Boerger, Jeff, 1977 (Box 209)
    Desires of A Changing Heart: A Soujourner's Life in the East
  - Brandi, Michael, 1976 (Box 209)
    Dumb Supper
  - Brashear, Joe Len, 2006 (Box 209)
  - Brondoli, Michael, undated (Box 209)
    And Now, Folks, The Dixie Bombshell
  - Bricuth, John, 1995 (Box 209)
    Let Me Say This About That
  - Broughton, T. Alan, 1973-1977 (Box 209)
    The Skin and All: Songs for the Cruelest Months
  - Brown, D. K., 2006 (Box 209)
    Leaving Eden
  - Brown, Lightning Allan, 1965, 1985-1994, 1994; 2 folders (Box 209)
    Poetry and Translation
  - Byers, Frederick, 1998 (Box 209)
    Silver Falls
  - Caldwell, Erskine, 1936 (Box 209)
    The Sacrilege of Alan Kent
  - Canin, Ethan, 1997 (Box 209)
    For Kings and Planets
  - Capers, Charlotte, 1977 (Box 209)
    Eudora Welty: A Friend's View
  - Chappell, Fred, 1959-1986, undated (Box 209)
    Le Soleil du Mal; Hallowind; For Reynolds; Teacher
  - Clem, Dean, 1996 (Box 209)
    Winds of Fury; Circles of Grace
  - Corrie, Daniel, 2001 (Box 209)
    What is Human Time?
  - Davenport, Guy and Benjamin Urrutia, 1996 (Box 210)
    The Logia of Yeshua
  - Davies, W. D., 1996 (Box 210)
    Reflections on Aspects of the Jewish Background of the Gospel of John
  - Davis, Bradford, undated (Box 210)
    Excerpts from untitled novel
  - Dickey, James, 1974-1981 (Box 210)
    The South Beheld; Jericho; Land and Water; Reynolds Price; Memoir of Dickey by his daughter, Bronwen
  - Donoghue, Denis, 1997, 2000, undated; 3 folders (Box 210)
    The Death of Satan; Eudora Welty's Sense of Place; The Practice of Reading
  - Dunn, Dale, undated (Box 210)
    Body Burden, script
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1961 (Box 210)
    Spring Mountain Climb
  - Emerson, Donald, 1962 (Box 210)
    Review of a Long and Happy Life
  - Erwin, John, 1972 (Box 210)
    A Manner of Calling
  - Esty, Jane, 1970 (Box 210)
    Green Elegy for a Child
  - Fellmeth, Michael Quixote, 1993 (Box 210)
    A Portrait of Devotion
  - Fleschner, Paul, 2003, 2008; 2 folders (Box 210)
    The Reinvention of Pollyanna Marcase; Children are Good (signed)
  - Foote, Horton, 1997, undated; 6 folders (Box 210)
    A Coffin in Egypt; Farewell: A Memoir of a Texas Childhood; Genesis of an American Playwright; 1918
  - Foote, Horton, undated (Box 211)
    1918
  - Fort, Charles, 1993 (Box 211)
    Poe's Daughter; Mr.Whore's Ruby Doll; Love; Photograph; It is a fearful thing to love what death can touch; Understudy; Superstitious Mountain; The Petrified Forest; The Ugly Man Behind the Little Wood
  - Fox, Jim, undated; 4 folders (Box 211)
    An Ascent from the Vault; The Great Bridge; Tar Beach; Two Rivers
  - Franck, Derek, 1997 (Box 211)
    A Yemeni Passage
  - Franklin, John Hope, 2005 (Box 211)
    North Carolina Conundrum
  - Fuller, R.C., undated (Box 211)
    Lunging in the Dark: Blindness and Vision, Disappointment and Aspiration in Reynold Price's Trilogy
  - Garfein, Herschel, 1993 (Box 211)
    From an American Book of the Death: Songs for Mezzo-Soprano and Piano
  - Garrett, George, 1978 (Box 211)
    Little Movie Without a Middle
  - Gibbs, Tom, 2006 (Box 211)
    The Water Gospel: A Long Poem
  - Gray, Francine du Plessix, 2000 (Box 211)
    The Work of Mourning (signed)
  - Grimsley, Jim, 1990, 1996; 2 folders (Box 211)
    A Bird of Prey; The Lizard of Tarsus
  - Guggenheim, Charles, 1996 (Box 211)
    Speaking of Reynolds Price: Outtakes from Clear Pictures
  - Gurganus, Allan, 1996 (Box 211)
    For Jack Fullilove (1917-2000)
  - Harris, Massimilla and C. T. B. Harris, 1991; 2 folders (Box 211)
  - Harris, Will, 2000 (Box 211)
    Will's Amazing, Fantastic, Hilarious, Horror Provoking; Witty, Smart Stories
  - Hassan, Ihab, 1997 (Box 211)
    The Expense of Spirit in Postmodern Times: Between Nihilism and Belief
  - Hauerwas, Stanley, 1994, 2004; 2 folders (Box 211)
    In Good Company: Preface and Chapter One; The Seven Words
  - Hays, Marguerite, 1972 (Box 211)
    Blackburn Article in Furman Magazine
  - Hays, Tommy, 2004, 2005; 3 folders (Box 212)
    The Pleasure was Mine
  - Helliker, Kevin, undated (Box 212)
    The Woodchopper
  - Hibbard, Tyrrell, 2003 (Box 212)
    The Speech of Angels: Paul, Acts, and Divine Communication with Humans
  - Humphries, Jeff, 1977-1990, 1995; 2 folders (Box 212)
    A Bestiary; Beyond the Pleasure Principle; Doctor, is my poem alright; Sermon Preached to a Mirror at Christmas Party in the Backwoods of Home; The Madness of Mrs. Crump; The Mirror's Eye; The Conjuror of Color; Poems
  - Inman, Will, 2006 (Box 212)
    Ranges
  - James, Sonja, 2004; 2 folders (Box 212)
    Children of the Moon:Poems by Sonia James; Girl in the wind, Fetching Fruit, A Brief Moment of Clarity, From Mobius
  - Johnson, Wallace Hank, 2004 (Box 212)
    The Looking Glass Conference
  - Jones, Michael Colby, 1998 (Box 212)
    One Hellgate Story
  - Jones, Paul, 1990 (Box 212)
    What the Welsh and Chinese Have in Common
  - Jorgenson, B. W., undated; 2 folders (Box 212)
    A Healing Soul on Reynolds Price's Purgatorial Endless Mountains; Pardon and Marriage: Three Stories
  - Justice, Jesse, 1991 (Box 212)
    An Elaborate Dialogue: Fate, Freewill, and Family in Reynolds Price's A Long and Happy Life and Kate Vaiden
  - Kaufman, Wallace, 1959-1964, undated (Box 212)
    Six Girls; River Meeting; Leukemia Age 3
  - Kelly, Tom, undated (Box 212)
    Waiting for Rain
  - Kenna, Michael, 1971-1974 (Box 212)
    Ten Poems for a Friend
  - Kimmel, Haven, 2001 (Box 212)
    The Solace of Leaving Early
  - Kizer, Carolyn, 1980-1986, undated (Box 212)
    Poems
  - Kreyling, Michael, 1982-1988, 1996; 2 folders (Box 213)
    Reynolds Price; The Extra; Men Without Women: Communities of Desire and Race in A Great Circle
  - Krueger, Robert and Kathleen, 2001 (Box 213)
    Cry from the Heart of Africa: A U.S. Ambassador's Family in Genocidal Burundi
  - Landesman, Peter, 1997 (Box 213)
    A Blood Acre: A Novel
  - Lang, David, undated (Box 213)
    The Weather Towel
  - Larson, Eric, 2000, undated; 2 folders (Box 213)
    Bermuda; The Pharisee's Gospel
  - Linney, Romulus, 1972-1985, 2001, undated; 3 folders (Box 213)
    Holy Ghosts; Woman Without a Name; Klonsky and Schwartz (signed); and Spain
  - Long, Paula Rosine, 2009 (Box 213)
    The Truth and the Word: The Gospels
  - Malouf, Melissa, 1997 (Box 213)
    It Had to Be You: The Joan and Ernest Story
  - Mann, Julian, III, 1988-1997 (Box 213)
    The Old Man and the Boy
  - Manning, Hank, undated (Box 213)
    Buzzbait
  - Marrs, Suzanne, 2002, 2005, undated; 6 folders (Box 231)
    One Writer's Imagination: The Fiction of Eudora Welty; The Huge Fateful Stage of the Outside World: Eudora Welty's Life in Politics; Eudora Welty: A Biography (correspondence and typescript with RP's annotations)
  - Massengill, David, 2001 (Box 213)
    "Scratchee and the Mermaid" "Scratchee's Sweet Valentine" (picture books)
  - Maunsell, Penelope, 1997 (Box 213)
    The Company of the Dead, screenplay of Price's short story
  - Maxwell, William, 1955 (Box 213)
    The Writer as Illusionist
  - McDonald, Robert M.S., 1998 (Box 213)
    Race, Sex and Reputation
  - McElheny, Sean, 1995 (Box 213)
    Lewis and Clark
  - McNelly, Liz, 1956 (Box 213)
    Letter to mom and dad, sent to Price in 2004
  - Meredith, William, 1977 (Box 213)
    For Two Lovers in the Canadian Woods a Hundred Years from Now
  - Millard, Charles, 1999 (Box 213)
    Oscar Comes to North Carolinas
  - Mills, David, undated (Box 214)
    Collected Poems, Money Bank and Spare Parts (Typescript), personal letter
  - Modjeska, Lee, 1994 (Box 214)
    Keeper of the Night: A Portrait of Life in the Shadow of Death
  - Moffatt, Jan E., 1995 (Box 214)
    When I'm Painting I Don't Have Cancer
  - Mofford, Frank, 1993 (Box 214)
    Phona; Solo Shoo-Shoo
  - Morgan, Robert, 1972, 2003; 3 folders (Box 214)
    ...Voice in the...; Brave Enemies
  - Moye, W. S., 1997 (Box 214)
    Examination of Joe Rollins Tract in Cleveland, Rutherford, and McDowell Counties, North Carolina
  - Payne, Peggy, 1994 (Box 214)
    Sister India
  - Peterson, Dwight N., 1997 (Box 214)
    A Gimp's-Eye View of the Healing of the Paralytic in Mark 2:1-2
  - Peterson, Mike, undated (Box 214)
    A Short and Unhappy Weekend
  - Plante, David, undated; 2 folders (Box 214)
    American Ghosts
  - Pollack, Harriet and Suzanne Marrs, eds., 2000 (Box 214)
    Eudora Welty and Politics: Did the Writer Crusade?
  - Pope, Deborah, undated; 2 folders (Box 215)
    Mortal World (typescript); Mortal World (advance uncorrected proofs)
  - Porter, Joe Ashby, 1962, 1996, 1981, undated; 4 folders (Box 215)
    Bone Key; St. Silvere's Head; Autumn Afternoon and Night; Two Stories (second draft)
  - Pratt, Minnie Bruce, 1997 (Box 215)
    Poems and Statement of Plans
  - Price, William, S., 1935, 1950, undated; 3 folders (Box 215)
    My Farewell-Dripping with Tears; Untitled Report; NC vs BC West Jr.; John Hope Franklin: A Life of Making History; Review of A Guide to the Historic Architecture of North Carolina
  - Rambo, Wiley Claude, 1993 (Box 215)
    Mint Chip and Plain Vanilla
  - Randall, Dale B.J., 1995, 2008; 2 folders (Box 215)
    American 'Mairzy' Dottiness, Sir John Fastolf Secretary, and the 'Law French' of a Caroline Cavalier; and, "Oh Yankee Soldier, Spare My Home!": the Wartime Rhymes of Robert Coffee (1839-1910)
  - Randolph, Leonard, 1976 (Box 215)
    Village Dying
  - Roberts, Nick, 2005 (Box 215)
    Garrett or Spray Paint Anniversary
  - Robinson, Marilyne, 1998 (Box 215)
    Death of Adam
  - Roth, Phillip, 1972 (Box 215)
    The Breast
  - Sartor, Margaret, 2004 (Box 215)
    A Real Girl in A Real Place
  - Schiff, James A., 1995, 1996-1997; 4 folders (Box 215)
    Understanding Reynolds Price; Critical Essays on Reynolds Price
  - Schiff, James A., 1996 (Box 216)
    Critical Essays on Reynolds Price
  - Sedgwick, Eve Kosofsky, 1999 (Box 216)
    A Dialogue on Love
  - Seymour, James, 1997 (Box 216)
    Holy Ghosts and Hidden Histories
  - Simkovic, Michael, undated (Box 216)
    Gottman's Night Out
  - Singer, William, 1967-1977, undated; 2 folders (Box 216)
    Poem A and Poem C; Eyes: A Gift; Revelation as Grace: A Study of the Twenty-Two Dreams in Surface of Earth
  - Sink, Alice E., undated (Box 216)
    What University Freshman Have Taught me About Reynolds Price's Novel, Kate Vaiden
  - Smith, Allen, 1996 (Box 216)
    Preacher: The Life of Reverend Helen Gray Crotwell
  - Smith, Amanda Joan Mackay, 2001 (Box 216)
    Eden Lost
  - Smith, Caleb, 2001, 2005; 3 folders (Box 216)
    Monumental (typescript); Monumental (second draft); Pirates
  - Smith, D. Moody, 2000, 2003-2004, undated; 7 folders (Box 216)
    Jesus of Nazareth: From Bornkamm to Sanders; John as Historian; When Did the Gospel Become Scripture?; Future Direction of Johannine Studies; Blind, but Now I See- a Sermon; Jesus Tradition in the Bible; The DaVinci Code review
  - Smith, Dave, 1988-1998, undated; 2 folders (Box 216)
    The Canoe in the Basement, Cuba Night, In Search of the Real Thing, Southern Crescent, To Isle of Wight, Why Southern Poetry May Be a Snipe Hunt
  - Smith, Dave, 1988-1999, undated; 3 folders (Box 217)
    Fate's Kite: Poems, The Righting Moment: Poems, The Wick of Memory: New and Selected Poems
  - Smith, Jean Kennedy and George Plimpton, 1993 (Box 217)
    Very Special Artists: Chronicles of Courage
  - Smith, R. T., 2003 (Box 217)
    Brightwood: Poems
  - Spencer, Elizabeth, 1996 (Box 217)
    Landscapes of the Heart: A Memoir
  - Spender, Stephen, 1939-1983, undated; 10 folders (Box 217)
    Engaged in Writing, (Typed draft), Engaged in Writing (Typescript), Engaged in Writing (Proof), Engaged in Writing (Volume), Engaged in Writing (Price's notes), The Connecting Imagination, The Fool and the Princess (Bound typescript), Journals, Adaption of Mary Stuart
  - Spender, Stephen, 1943-1983, 1986, undated; 20 folders (Box 218)
    Journals, Adaption of Mary Stuart, Schiller's "Mary Stuart," (Handwritten draft), Schiller's "Mary Stuart," (Manuscript), Schiller's "Mary Stuart," (Typescript), Schiller's "Mary Stuart," (Fourth draft), Schiller's "Mary Stuart," (Published pages), The Temple, Essays, Proofs
  - Spender, Stephen, 1960-1983, undated; 3 folders (Box 219)
    Book Jackets, Poetry, Essays
  - Spivey, Robert, 2005 (Box 219)
    Prologue: The Nature of the New Testament
  - Stokes, Adrian, undated (Box 219)
    Vermeer and Degas
  - Stokes, Harry, 1967, 1995-1996; 3 folders (Box 219)
    untitled
  - Store of Joys: Writers Celebrate the North Carolina Museum of Art's Fiftieth Anniversary, 1995-1996; 2 folders (Box 219)
    The Store of Joys: Writers Celebrate the North Carolina Museum of Art's Fiftieth Anniversary
  - Styron, William, 1974 (Box 219)
    A Life Sketch #1; A Life Sketch #2
  - Sutherland, John, 2000, undated; 3 folders (Box 219)
    Stephen Spender: The Authorized Biography
  - Sutherland, John, 2000, undated; 6 folders (Box 220)
    Stephen Spender: The Authorized Biography, Stephen Spender: The Authorized Biography, (Second draft), Stephen Spender: The Authorized Biography, (Second draft)
  - Taliaferro, Marguerite, 1972 (Box 221)
    The Dolphin Sleep (Typescript)
  - Tamplin, Ronald, undated (Box 221)
    The Catechumen
  - Tate, Allen, 1979 (Box 221)
    All is Brillig (or ought to be), numbered, limited edition of Tate's last published poem
  - Tompkins, Jane, undated (Box 221)
    Let's Get Lost
  - Torgovnick, Marianna, 1997 (Box 221)
    Primitive Passions: Men, Women, and the Quest for Ecstasy
  - Turner, Robert, 2004 (Box 221)
    Chasm, first chapter sample; letter from Jim Carpenter; and, letter from Garday Literary Agency.
  - Tyler, Anne, 1959 (Box 221)
    In Sudden Solitude: A Critical Essay from a Rising Sophomore
  - Vaughn, Caroline, 1995 (Box 221)
    Notes on Borrowed Time and career narrative
  - Vauthier, Simone, 1974, undated; 2 folders (Box 221)
    The Circle in the Forest: Fictional Space in A Long and Happy Life, Reasonable Uses of the Unreasonable: The Supernatural in Reynolds Price's Love and Work
  - Verdelle, A. J., 1995 (Box 221)
    The Good Negress
  - Verghese, Abraham, 1998 (Box 221)
    The Tennis Partner
  - Voll, Daniel, 1950, 1992-1995, 2002-2005, undated; 11 folders (Box 221)
    Dear Mr. President, (Typescript); Dear Mr. President, (Second draft); The Flying Saucer Cafe; Free Falling; Moon Child; Riot Baby; To the Shoreline; Skin; Threat Matrix; Threat Matrix: Episode 104; In Plane Sight; and Cape Town (1984).
  - Wagenknecht, Edward, 1950 (Box 222)
    Dickens and the Scandalmongers
  - Waller, Susan B., 2005 Apr (Box 222)
    Haddon
  - Wasserman, Harriet, undated (Box 222)
    Handsome Is: Adventures with Saul Bellow
  - Weldon, Will, undated (Box 222)
    My Brother, A Muslim, screenplay
  - Wells, Charles, 2005 (Box 222)
    Clyde
  - Welty, Eudora, 1955, 1970-1972, 2003, undated; 6 folders (Box 222)
    A Flock of Guinea Hens Seen from a Car, One Time, One Place, Place in Fiction, One Writer's Beginnings, (Typescript with notes), The Optimist's Daughter, (Galleys with notes), The Optimist's Daughter (Typescript with notes), Proofs; The Night of the Little House
  - West, James L. W., III, 1995, undated; 3 folders (Box 222)
    Duke, Second Stint; Durham and Flatbush, Styron in Paris, Styron at Duke
  - West, John Cameron, undated (Box 222)
    A Sidebar to 'Esse Quam Videri'
  - Wilbur, Richard, 1981 (Box 222)
    Pedestrian Flight
  - Wilkinson, Alec, 1992; 2 folders (Box 222)
    A Murder
  - Wilkinson, Alec, 1994, 2001; 3 folders (Box 223)
    My Mentor; untitled
  - Williams, Rowan, 2003 (Box 223)
    The Poems of Rowan Williams
  - Willingham, Dan, 1996, 1995; 2 folders (Box 223)
    American 'Mairzy' Dottiness, Sir John Fastolf's Secretary, and the 'Law French' of a Caroline Cavalier; and, "Oh Yankee Soldier, Spare My Home!": the Wartime Rhymes of Robert Coffee (1839-1910)
  - Willimon, William H., 1993, 1995; 2 folders (Box 223)
    We Work Hard, We Play Hard': A Report for the President and the Provost, and the Vice President of Student Life of Duke University; Tell me the Story of Jesus
  - Willrich, Patricia Rowe, 1991, 1992; 2 folders (Box 223)
    A Perspective on Wallace Stegner; Watching Through Windows: A Perspective on Anne Tyler
  - Wilson, Robert, 1995 (Box 223)
    Untitled
  - Woodhouse, Walter, 1971 (Box 223)
  - Wright, Stuart and James L. W. West, 1985; 6 folders (Box 223)
    A Bibliography of the Writings of Reynolds Price, Typescript A; Typescript B; Typescript C
  - Wright, Stuart and James L. W. West, 1985; 5 folders (Box 224)
    A Bibliography of the Writings of Reynolds Price, Typescript D;Typescript: (Price's copy with holograph corrections); Proof; Sketches for frontispiece
  - Wronoski, Jim, 2003 (Box 224)
    The Fine Line of Faith (Poem); Letter from Wronoski
  - Yoden, Edwin, undated; 2 folders (Box 224)
    Lions at Lamb House (Draft)
  - Yungblut, June, 1986 (Box 224)
    The Entered Heart
  - Miscellaneous writings by indeterminable authors, 1953-1999, 2003, undated; 5 folders (Box 224)
    A Selected Bio-Bibliography of Reynolds Price, by Barbara R. Swain; Reynolds Price: A Bibliography, by Clayton Owens (Working draft with corrections by Price); Miscellaneous Bibliographies; Dictionary of Literary Biography; Proof for entry on Price for American Short Story Writers Since World War II, Second Series, Vol. 218; Proof for entry on Price for American Novelists Since World War II, Seventh Series, Vol. 278